Never forget why you are the church.
So, Romans chapter 11.
We're gonna jump right back in.
We've kind of taken a 2 week break talking about eternal security and
how the fact that we cannot lose our salvation.
But we're gonna jump back into the exposition and contextual understanding
of this chapter.
Now, remember, Romans not through 11
have primarily been directed to
a Jewish audience.
Paul is explaining the hard truth of why
all Israelites at that time were not saved.
Again, if you were a Jew, especially in a time of
the apostle Paul, this would be a hard pill to swallow,
because they'd be thinking, hold on, we're God's people.
We're God's chosen nation.
What do you mean?
that not all Jews are saved?
But since they rejected Christ, listen, then they were lost, right?
You cannot be saved a sign from Christ.
Amen?
The end of chapter 11 serves as a tied up
bow to this discussion of Israel.
He brings things to an understanding that I
believe help us today in the cultural, political,
and geographical landscape that we find ourselves in.
So we're going to look at Romans chapter 11.
I'm going to read verses 25 through 32
and then we'll get going.
If you're there, say read.
He says, for I would not, brethren, that
she should be ignorant of this mystery.
lest you should be wise in your own conceits,
that blindness in part is happen to Israel
until the fullness of the Gentiles become in.
And so all Israel shall be saved as it
is written there shall come out of Zion, the deliverer and shall
turn away on godliness from Jacob.
For this is my covenant unto them when I shall
take away their sins, as concerning the gospel,
they are enemies for your sake, but as touching the election,
they are beloved for the Father's sake.
For the gifts and calling of God are without repentance.
For as ye in times past have not believed God, yet have
now obtained mercy through their unbelief, even so,
even so have these also have not believed,
now have not believed that through your mercy, they also may obtain mercy.
For God had concluded them all in unbelief that he might have mercy
upon, oh, we're continuing the theme,
how unsearchable.
How unsearchable.
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you for your word.
I thank you for just a sweet time of worship.
God, I pray, Lord, that we live our life in that kind of worship God, because you're worthy of it.
No matter what we say or do, may it all be to your glory.
But God, just for the next few moments, Lord, I pray that you give
me clarity, wisdom and freedom to preach your word, God.
Would I pray that we take your word, God,
as what it is, and that is the truth, the eternal infallible truth.
God, we thank you, we love you.
Speak to us today, in Jesus name.
Amen.
Three things I want us to leave here understanding.
We're going to go over 2 of them today and then one of them next week.
But 1st we see the mystery.
We see the mystery.
Look again verses 25 through 27.
It says this, for I were not, brethren, that you should be ignorant of this mystery.
Lest you should be wise in your own conceits, that blindness
in part is happened to Israel until
the fullness of the Gentiles be come in.
And so verse 26, all Israel shall be saved,
as it is written, there shall come out of Zion, the deliverer,
and shall turn away ungodliness from Jacob.
For this is my covenant unto them.
When I shall take away their sins.
Now these 3 verses are jam-packed with information that we need to know.
It is important to note that when Paul uses the word mystery, it is
not necessarily means something hard to be understood.
Today we think of a mystery as something confusing, right?
Something that takes much investigating to figure out.
Well, here's the thing.
This is a truth.
When he talks to the word a mystery.
That's not what he is intending.
As a matter of fact, this term mystery literally means a
sacred secret secret.
This is a truth that was previously unrevealed
by God, but is now being revealed by
God through his word.
By the way, I want you to know something.
There are many places in scripture that can be confounding.
There are many places in scripture to where we could have a discussion
and lead that discussion no matter how long we discuss and
still agree to disagree.
Amen?
That's just part of the infallible
and the eternal word of God, right?
We're going to talk more about that next week, how unsearchable he is.
But I can tell you this.
The majority of scripture is not like that.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Don't miss what I'm trying to put down here.
We so often, because we get intimidated
by the word of God, we say, well, you know what?
I just don't understand this, and everyone argues about this,
and that if you would just read God's word, you would be
shocked at the unction of the Holy Spirit, what he would
reveal to you through his word, because in reality, when
he says, be doers of the word, not just hearers, he's going
to give you the power to be able to do.
And that means to understand.
Listen, people all the time tell me, I don't know what God's will is in my life.
Just read.
Listen, there's scripture that says, hey, this is God's will for your life.
Be thankful.
You understand what I'm saying?
There's a lot of areas of scripture where it is not confusing.
It is not confounding.
However, I understand that this is can
be confusing today.
So that's why I believe that Paul is very straight up with this.
Look at what Paul says in verse 25.
For I would not, brethren, that you should be ignorant of this mystery.
That word ignorant also can be translated uninformed.
Church, God does not reveal everything to us.
But what he does reveal to us, he makes plain as day.
And we have no excuse to be uninformed.
I was talking to Miss
DeLee this morning.
We were talking.
Yeah, I'm not lying.
Let them know.
And she was, well, she
was kind of making fun of how long I am in my series of books and so, you know, whatever.
It hurt my feelings for like 2 seconds, and I was like, whatever.
But, no, and she was like, I remember when you were in Genesis, because we were talking to
somebody, and I think they said, they said, well, you know, we're going to be in Romans for a long, long time.
And then this was her response.
Do you remember when we were in Genesis?
And so, we did take a long time.
But either way, um, but it was awesome because she said this.
She came and she asked, how long are we going to be in Genesis?
Like, I know these things.
I grew up in the, you know, in the Bible, I grew up in church.
She's a PK.
s a preacher's kid.
She, you know, but here's what my response was.
Hey, listen, there's a lot of people that don't.
The foundational, really what you would call elementary,
uh, aspects of God's word.
There's a lot of people that don't know it.
So what I'm trying to say is, listen, when we sit here
and we look at God's word, we have an
uninformed society, we have an uninformed
culture, listen, you can see it in a political scheme.
People want to act like they know scripture to get votes.
They do not know scripture.
Just because someone tells you and quote scripture to you
real quick and says they love Jesus, do not be deceived.
If it is not aligned with the full God of word, then it is untrue.
Amen.
That's why we got to...
y'all women this morning.
Amen.
So anyway, we don't want to be uninformed, so we're going to dig deep into this.
But what is this sacred secret?
What is God revealing to us?
Well, if you look again in verse 25, that blindness
in part has happened to Israel, until the
fullness of the Gentiles become in.
Paul is explaining what is happening to Israel, not just 2000
years ago, but also today.
By the way, you do realize that we have what I believe is recency
bias in our culture.
The only perspective that we have, especially my generation
in the younger generations is whatever is happening today,
this is, we got to start building our theology around what's happening today.
You know what that creates?
That creates a culture in our churches.
It says God's word is no longer relevant.
Can I tell you, that is a deception from the devil.
God's word is real.
By the way, there's nothing you under the sun.
You think you're the 1st generation that has seen all this stuff?
Now I'm not saying that, you know, back in, there's people that think that
before the flood, they had technology and stuff, I don't know.
I don't think so.
But all I'm trying to say is when it comes to sin when it comes to
our human nature, when it comes to all these things, they can separate
for us from God, nothing is new.
It's been around for a long, long time.
So he says right here, in order to punish Israel's rejection, he has blinded them.
They have been in the state for a while.
They have been hardened.
That word blinded relates to the state of stubbornness.
Something God had warned against and punished all throughout
Israel's history.
But there's some details here to this.
First off, if you want to look at the hardening, this hardening
1st detail is partial.
There has always been a remnant of Israel who has believed.
As a matter of fact, the one who wrote this letter, the apostle
Paul, was a born-again believer in Jesus Christ.
Amen?
But he was also a Jew, right?
And so he even in scripture, he lays
out his credibility of being a Jew.
But the hardening is partial.
He mentions this in Romans 11, if we go back to verse five,
even so then at this present time, he's speaking.
There is a remnant according to the election of grace.
Just as today, there are Israelites who have put
their faith in Jesus, even though the nation of Israel and
the Jewish state as a whole is in blindness and stubbornness
towards God.
As a matter of fact, that's what you would call a messianic Jew.
They acknowledge Jesus Christ as
the Messiah.
Secondly, not only is it partial, but
this is a temporary hardening.
Look again, the blindness in part has happened to Israel.
Until the fullness of the Gentiles become in.
The time of the Gentiles is a period where God has shifted his
focus from Israel to the rest of the world.
Here is where God makes it obvious that Israel is
not the church and the church is not Israel.
Although there can be overlap.
In other words, listening, an Israelite can become part of the church,
but there are there's a separate thing.
There is Israel and then there is the church.
Now, as a New Testament believer, we are brought into
the blessings of Israel through the faith of Abraham,
meaning when we put our faith in Jesus as Abraham
did so long ago, we become partakers in the blessing.
By the way, praise God for that.
Amen?
That's what I'm talking about.
If this was not so, why even mention
Israel and the church separately?
Why is why is there even different language used?
Understand, he is speaking to the believers in Rome.
This is who he's writing to, but yet he speaks of the Israelites as well.
So be careful with your theology on that.
Listen, I don't believe the church has replaced Israel.
I believe God still has that ever lasting covenant
with Israel.
But here's the thing.
If this was not true, why does Paul tell believing Gentiles,
obviously the church, do not be arrogant towards Israel.
Are y'all with me this morning?
Here's one of the main oppositional points to Israel being Israel today.
Well, preacher, most of Israel today are atheists and Christian haters.
They are a wicked nation.
Okay.
May I remind you of Romans 3, verses 3 and four?
This is why if you're not careful, And
you just take these ideas from our culture, And
you don't look at scripture, you do realize that a
lot of these questions that we're asking today can just be answered in scripture.
Look at Romans chapter 3, verse 3 through 4.
For what if some did not believe?
Shall their unbelief make the faith of God without effect?
God forbid.
Yea, let God be true, but every man a liar?
As it is written thou, that thou mightest be justified in
thy sayings, and mightest overcome when thou art judged?
You know, I also want to say this, if we would focus on
our own sin and the sin of the saints as
much as we did on lost people's sins, we'd
see some true holiness in the church.
Amen?
We love to point the finger
and say, oh, look, those lost people acting lost.
You know what?
Hey, you know what we should rather say according to rebuke that we see
in God's word, hold on, why are the Christians acting lost?
That's contrary to our new nature.
Aren't you glad there's nothing that we can do to nullify the
promises of God?
By the way, I was talking today.
You know, if you could lose your salvation, you done lost it?
I mean, are you kidding me right now?
Has anybody sinned this week?
You have?
I don't get too excited.
Amen?
Yes, sir, preacher.
I'm glad you asked.
I need to confess some things.
We can do that later, okay?
But think about it.
Of course you sinned.
guess what?
You know what that means?
That means if you could lose it, now, if
it was contingent on what you did, right?
Before all holy, thrice holy almighty
God, you in that definition are in a sinful state, therefore,
boom, you've lost your salvation.
And the Bible even says that if that happens in Hebrews, hey, there's no repentance left for you.
So if you believe that you could lose your salvation, you also have to believe that you cannot
obtain it again.
And you just admitted to me that you sinned this week.
So we're all going to hell.
That's what that doctrine teaches.
Amen?
Someone's going to cut that and make a very, very odd reel.
But anyway.
You see what I'm saying, though, church, you understand what I'm trying to get to?
We got to be careful.
Here's the thing.
Nothing can nullify the promises of God.
God promises us salvation through Jesus Christ, and God
promised Israel to be restored.
As God focuses on the gospel being spread around the world.
He will soon turn his focus back on Israel.
Why is this mystery important for us to know?
Well, look again at verse 25,
It's all right here.
For I were not, brethren, that ye should be ignorant of this mystery.
Look, lest you should be wise in
your own conceits.
This is exactly what we're seeing today.
People are wise according to their own estimation.
They think they have God and his plan all figured out.
They believe that since we are a New Testament, that,
well, we're New Testament believers, so the Old Testament doesn't
have any relevance today.
That's already done with.
We're in a new covenant, so forget the old covenant.
Let me just tell you something.
Church, some things are hard to understand.
Amen, would you agree with that?
Can I tell you what's not hard to understand?
An everlasting covenant?
What does everlasting mean?
Forever.
And by the way, for the people that say, oh, and I believe that every promise
is yes and amen through Jesus Christ, just right when they when
Israel gets restored, it's going to be through faith in Jesus Christ.
But what I'm trying to say is there's some people that say, well, when Jesus
ascended or when Jesus resurrected, rather, all
the promises, all the prophecies, they were all fulfilled, there's
no covenant left, it's just Jesus.
Well, then why is Paul still writing about it?
Why is he still talking about the covenant?
Why is he still talking about a future restoration if it's already happened?
Amen.
Maybe be humbled by the hardening of Israel and not be deceived.
Whenever we see people far from God, it should turn our hearts closer to
the gospel, and in doing so, it should compel us to share the
good news that saved us.
So we see this mystery is explained in such a way that we know when and why,
but there's another level to it.
Look at verses 26 through 27.
And so all Israel shall be saved.
As it is written, there shall come out of Zion, a deliverer,
and shall turn away on godliness from Jacob, for this is my covenant
unto them when I shall take away their sins.
Now Paul is quoting 2 Old Testament scriptures here.
We're going to read some Old Testament.
So go ahead and take a drink of your energy drink, okay?
All right?
By the way, for those that aren't getting good rest at night, I've
noticed that some people in Romans 11 have been starting to sleep a little
bit more, I'm going to start calling out your name.
Amen?
All right?
Okay, so just know if you're sleeping, you better hope I don't know your name.
Okay, anyway.
Isaiah 59, verse 20 says this.
And the Redeemer shall come to Zion and unto them that turn from
transgression and Jacob saith the Lord, as for me, this is my
covenant with them, saith the Lord.
My spirit that is upon thee, and my words, which I have put
in thy mouth, shall not depart out of thy mouth, nor
out of the mouth of thy seed, nor out of the mouth of thy seed seed,
saith the Lord, from henceforth and forever.
Also Isaiah chapter 27, going
back in the book there in verse 9.
By this, therefore, shall the iniquity of Jacob be purged.
And this is all the fruit to take away his sin.
When he maketh all the stones of the altar as chalk stones that are beaten in sunder.
The groves and images shall not stand up.
Another one, we see this as well in Jeremiah chapter
31, starting in verse 33, but this shall be the covenant
that I will make with the house of Israel.
After those days, said, Lord, I'll put my law in their
inward parts and write it in their hearts and will be their God
and they shall be my people.
And they shall teach no more.
Every man is neighbor, and every man is brother, saying, know the Lord, for they
shall all know me, for the least of them unto the greatest of them, saith
the Lord, for I will forgive their iniquity, and I will remember their sin no more.
These are the scriptures that Paul, in the New Testament,
is taking from the Old Testament to talk of a future event.
What does this mean?
The statement all Israel shall be say does not mean that every
Jew alive when Christ returns will be saved.
or even rather delivered.
Ezekiel, chapter 20, starting in
verse 34, speaks on this.
And again, I know we're doing a lot of scripture here.
Just bear with me.
And I'll bring you out from the people and I will gather you out of the countries wherein
you are scattered with a mighty hand and with a stretched out arm.
And with fury poured out.
And I'll bring you into the wilderness of the people and there will be, and
there will I plead with you face to face like as I pleaded
with your fathers in the wilderness of the land of Egypt, so will I plead with you, saith the Lord God.
And I will cause you to pass under the rod, and it'll bring you into
the bond of the covenant, and I'll purge out from among you, the rebels.
And then the transgress against me.
And I will bring them forth out of the country where they sojourn, sojourn,
and they shall not enter into the land of Israel, for for
ye shall know that I am the Lord.
The theologian and biblical historian F. F. Bruce explained it like this.
All Israel is a recurring expression in Jewish literature.
Where it need not mean every Jew without a single exception.
But rather Israel as a whole.
For example, Do you think that our country
was founded on Christian principles?
Talking about the United States of America.
Amen?
Do you think our country, when it was founded, was consistent of only Christians?
But we were a Christian nation.
You see the concept here.
This is similar to the fact that the fullness of the Gentiles does
not mean all Gentiles, but rather those who have put their faith
in Christ.
I need to make this clear.
No one has ever been saved aside
from faith in Jesus Christ.
is impossible.
It cannot happen.
This consists and includes the Old Testament, and New Testament saints.
The Jews are no different regarding their salvation.
I appreciate the clarity the home and New Testament commentary brings to this.
Let me read to you this point here.
Paul's point here is that in the future, when the
elect of the Gentiles have been saved, the hardening
currently afflicting Israel will be removed and all Israel
will resume its position as the elect people of God before him.
At that point, salvation of individuals will
occur as it did for Paul and always has on
the basis of personal faith in Israel's savior
and Messiah, Jesus Christ.
So there's the mystery.
It's partially and temporarily hardened
Israel is.
And in the meantime, God has shifted his focus on the Gentiles.
Once this time comes to its fullness.
God will once again focus on Israel.
Again, this is not a new problem.
Israel didn't just all of a sudden become what it is today.
By the way, I will say this.
you know, understand that in
1948 when they become, when they became acknowledged as
a as a nation, right, before that, they were scattered even more than they are now.
It's miraculous to even see what's going on.
Not only that, it should give us humility to
understand that even though they may be wicked, even though they may
be far from God, God is still keeping his promise to them.
Even in the meantime, punishing them.
Do we not serve a mighty God?
God will establish his new covenant by writing the law upon their hearts rather
than through outward legislation.
He will do this through Jesus.
There will be a remnant that turns their life to Christ.
Now, what does this mean specifically?
Well, next we see, we just saw the mystery.
Y'all want me to say amen?
Okay?
If you're not, just sit quietly, okay?
But next we see the master plan.
Look at verses 28 through 29.
As concerning the gospel,
They are enemies for your sakes.
But as touching the election, they are beloved
for the Father's sakes, for the gifts and callings of God.
or without repentance.
Notice the language used here.
They, meaning Israel, are enemies for our sakes, enemies of who?
Enemies of what?
Well, the Bible makes it very clear, the gospel.
God is dealing with Israel as an enemy in our present moment.
Once again, this is evidence with how secular Israel is today.
I look this up, that you know that today, one.
9% of Israel claims Christ is Lord.
One.9%.
Church, praise God for our fellow saints in Israel, but that's not a lot.
You understand what I'm saying there?
8% claim to be fully convinced
atheists.
There is no God.
There's nothing.
By the way, atheism and agnosticism.
There's 2 different things, although atheism is a religion, I believe.
Because you have a belief that there is nothing to believe in.
You what I mean?
So how silly is that?
But so you have atheism, there's nothing.
And then you have agnostics that there's probably something that just, I don't care about it.
And they don't care about us.
You see it?
You see the difference there?
But 8% Israel are fully convinced atheists.
Up to 25% of Israeli Jews do
not believe in a deity.
18% of the total population of Israel today
practice Islam.
Well, I'm gonna add something here.
We need to understand that Islam is contrary to biblical Christianity.
I'm not talking about radical Islam.
That is obviously far from God.
Okay?
By the way, I want you to know some.
Doesn't matter where you stand.
Unless you stand with Jesus, anything radical is bad.
Are y'all with me?
We got people that love to be radical towards this
system of theology, and that system of theology.
We're radical towards this and we're radical towards that.
We got to be careful trying to have all the answers.
Okay?
We got to come to God's word humility.
But we're not talking about the radical Islamists.
We're talking about the average Islamic person is
living in opposition to the truth in God's word.
I not saying they don't do good things.
I'm not saying they may not be good people according to what
the world thinks with that, although we know that Roman said there's none righteous, no, not one.
That includes us, and that includes them.
That includes everybody.
But I'm saying in what they believe.
Islam rejects the triune God.
They don't believe in the Trinity.
They reject the deity of Christ and intensely reject
any idea of Calvary.
They can say all they want.
They accept the Bible as well.
They say, well, you know, we read the Bible too, but they foundationally
hold to the Quran being the final word and full authority giving from
Allah who they call God.
The issue with this is the Quran was written by Muhammad around the 7th century.
The Bible was completed and sealed.
in the 1st century.
Proverbs 30 verse 6, add thou not unto his words, lest
he reprove thee, and thou be find a liar.
You know what that tells me?
If you try to add the God's word, you're going to be found a liar.
Revelation 22, verse 18 and 19, for I testify
unto every man that hear the words of the prophecy of this book.
If any man shall add unto these things, God shall add unto him
the plagues that are written in this book.
And if any man shall take away from the words of the book of this prophecy, God
shall take away his part out of the book of life and out of the holy city
and from the things which are written in this book.
So 18% of Israel are practicing Islam and 30% of the Jews
are either atheists or non-religious church.
You may not think that's a big deal, but we're talking about an obviously
blinded people.
They are enemies of the gospel.
And it's for our sake.
Think about that for a second.
God is doing all this.
so that we could come into the fold.
Once again, that should humble us today.
But from the standpoint of God's choice, look at what scripture says in verse
28, but as touching the election, they are beloved for the Father's sake.
Because God chose Abraham.
When Paul is speaking of the Father's sake, notice
that's not a capital F.
He's speaking of the fathers of the faith.
So when he chose Abraham and Isaac and Jacob, he
loves the nation and will carry through in his promises, this is another
reason why their hardening is temporary.
Now look at verse 29, for the gifts and calling of God are without repentance.
I like the word used in NASB 95.
It says it's for the gifts and the calling of God are
irrevocable.
God will not revoke his promise, not to Abraham,
not to Isaac, not to Jacob, and
not to you and not to me.
Do not become deceived on your own understanding.
It is easy to look at the current events and attempt in making an opinion based on the present.
But Ruler the present has been going on in the past a whole long time.
God's plan is clear regarding Israel.
Their failure to respond made them an enemy of God.
In doing so, the gospel was brought to the Gentiles.
When God calls, he does not revoke that call.
Therefore, his everlasting promise will still stand.
To Israel.
Nothing can happen between now and then that we'll change that.
Church, do you realize this is good news?
Like, I understand that we've been talking about Israel a whole lot.
I understand we've been talking about moments 9 through 11,
Every time I talk to a pastor and I they say, hey, what are you preaching?
I say, I'm in Romans 9 or I'm in Romans 10.
And every pastor, oh,
Oh, oh.
Good luck with that, right?
But here's the thing, though.
When you go through a book of the Bible, You just go through it.
You don't get to skip, you don't get to move around, you just go through it.
And so this is important for us to know, or it wouldn't be in God's Word.
And aren't, isn't it amazing?
Hear me now.
With all the things going on, we just so happen to be in Romans 11.
I didn't plan that.
I don't have that kind of pull.
Amen?
I didn't say, hey, I'm in Romans 11.
Can you do something crazy in Israel?
I didn't do that.
But God is working his plan.
And I believe that he wants us to not be uninformed.
But he wants us to understand.
We serve a faithful God.
In our times of hardness of heart and rebellion, he still keeps us.
He still calls us his own.
What does that leave you today?
I can tell you where it should leave all of us.
Right out the gate without any more exposition, it should leave us thankful.
That's the simplest, that's the simplest application I could give you
today is be thankful to God.
But I can tell you, This being good
news and understanding the faithfulness.
And just everything that goes in with God being who he is, it's
amazing to me that we've just talked about, Israel being hardened.
And blinded spiritually, far from God, yet we, the
church, are here gathered today.
And I just, and God put us on my heart before, and I
kind of just, I kept it in for a little bit, but I want you to know,
I understand and maybe some people here today that, man, your joy is gone.
It's nonexistent.
Your your peace, your contentment.
You may be here, but you're not really here.
Understand what you're missing out on, even being here, what you're missing out on.
What we're doing right now.
Do you realize the master plan, the things that
had to take place, the precious blood of Jesus,
that had to be spilled?
so that we could do what we're doing.
Oh, well, preacher, the church didn't gather like this.
We're gathered in the name of Jesus right now.
I don't care if the 1st century church had pews.
Really, they just stood up the entire time.
Listen, half of y'all would have passed, done out.
So thank God for views.
But what I'm trying to say is we come in here and we try to make every
excuse and we try to we try to just go week by week by week.
Let me explain what's going to happen.
If you continue in discontentment.
If you continue without peace, if you continue without joy,
at some point, what happens if you just don't continue?
anymore?
If the enemy in this world steals your effectiveness.
I can tell you right now, you know what I pray for this morning?
I prayed for us to enjoy being here today.
I pray for us to enjoy God today.
In everything that we do.
And we enjoy them.
Yesterday, Carlos, over the house, we were cutting down a tree.
Carl was pretty good at that.
I was just dragging limbs.
He was like up there like a, I mean, I mean, really high.
River was like, man, that dude is in that tree.
I'm like, yeah.
If he follows, we want to drag him out because I ain't
trying to pay for nothing, but anyway, no, I just can't...
We were in a tree, and we were working, and man, it was hot.
And here's what I'm talking about, and everything.
No matter what it is.
It was hot, we were sweaty.
And we're finishing up, man, and we're looking at this finished work.
I'm in a pile, you can't even see over it.
It is insane.
I hope the city picks it up.
But anyway, And he said, right,
we both had the same thought at the same time.
God, thank you for this little overcast right now.
Now don't don't miss me.
I know this is so silly.
We were hot, we were sweaty.
We're working.
And he said at first, he beat me to it.
He's more spiritual.
But he said, man, thank you, God, for this.
Like, there's clouds covering the sun a little bit.
It's still nice, but man, this is just nice.
Carlos, I was just thinking that.
Now, you might think that's silly, but we in the same moment,
In our hearts, I believe, according to the Holy
Spirit, was going to thank the same God for the same thing in the same moment.
We were sweaty, we were tired of working, yet we were thankful.
Don't miss this.
Today, are you thankful?
Today, are you do you have the joy of the Lord in your life?
No matter what's going on.
listen, hey, we can talk about Israel all day long.
We can talk about geopolitics.
We can talk about who's got a new coup.
We can do all these things.
It doesn't matter.
We can talk about end times on Wednesday night.
God did not design us to serve
him without joy.
God knows what he is doing.
Listen, I don't know what's going on in your life.
You might be here thinking, hey, preacher, it's easy for you to say that.
You got all these things going on.
Hey, listen, 1st off, hang out for a little bit.
You'll find out that ain't how it is.
But no matter what's going on in your life.
Listen, hey, through the good times, through the bad times,
through the, okay times, through the difficult times, through the confusing times.
It does not matter.
God knows what he's doing.
The mystery has been revealed, and his master plan is in place.
What's our part?
Look up.
Look up, and be ready.
Next week, we're gonna talk about his mercy, but today, let me ask you, do you trust his plan?
What is going on in your life that you feel as though God has forsaken you?
Where in your walk is your faith weak?
God is with us for the long haul.
We are his for eternity.
Sometimes it takes time for this to come to fruition, his plan.
So it has about us close over this place.